Sanjog Thapa

Huntsville, AL, USA | +1 (256) 694 - 8208 | sanzog03@gmail.com | linkedin | www.sanjogthapa.com.np

PROFILE AND OBJECTIVE

I'm a Software developer who enjoys the process of problem-solving and turning ideas into reality. I'm always looking to expand my knowledge, improve upon old skills, and learn new ones. For the past 5 years, I've been working with JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, and Python to help bring about solutions for our company's internal, as well as outside. Currently, I am pursuing a Master's in Computer and Information Science as a Graduate Research Assistant specializing in data mining, simulations, and cloud. Looking for a job after my graduation.

SKILLS

Language: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, GoLang, C, C++, Java, Matlab, Ruby

Frameworks: ReactJS, ExpressJS, React Native, Jquery, Rails

Data Tools: Numpy, Pandas, Xarray, Scipy, Seaborn, CesiumJS, CZML, 3Dtiles, chartJS

Database: PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, DynamoDB

Build Tools: Webpack, Terraform, Docker

Version Management: Git

Testing Tools: CucumberJS, Chai

Tools: NodeJS/NPM, RabbitMQ, WebSockets, AWS Lambda, AWS EC2, AWS S3, Linux/Bash, Spreadsheets

WORK EXPERIENCE

NASA GHRC DAAC, ITSC UAH

Huntsville, AL, USA

Full Stack / Graduate Research Assistant

Aug 2022 - Present

- Collaborated with NASA scientists to develop a cloud-based interactive visualization playground, providing a more comprehensive view of atmospheric science data collected during field campaigns.
- Implemented a cloud-based data subsetting tool utilizing a serverless microservice architecture in Python, resulting in a more efficient and streamlined process for subsetting prime instruments data.
- Developed a cloud-based visualization and simulation tool with data mining processes to represent the big data over a 3D globe, efficiently in a browser.
- Collaborated on a lightning data visualization in a live notebook environment, resulting in an increased understanding of the open-source project by attendees during UWG meetup.

GURZU INC Lalitpur, Nepal

Software Engineer

Aug 2020 - Aug 2022

- Write scalable full-stack applications using ReactJS, ElectronJS, and ExpressJS along with volunteering as a mentor for trainees in the project.
- Standardized Nodejs back-end project flow and build requirements inside the company.
- Worked closely with the product designer and stakeholders to understand and build custom features in digital ads software, catering to the local market, resulting in a significant 40% revenue boost for the local signage industry.
- Volunteer for team activities inside a company to discuss and share recent trends, ideas, and problems faced and learned by the various members while working with multiple teams and stakeholders.

JYAASA TECHNOLOGIES

Kathmandu, Nepal

Associate Software Engineer

Jan 2019 - Aug 2020

- Integrate with third-party services, external REST APIs, and resilient messaging with RabbitMQ as a part of the implementation of desktop applications for digital signage (digital billboard ads) software solutions.
- Implement authentication backend and web sockets for real-time messaging service.
- Participating in peer code reviews for applications ensuring compliance with the company coding standards.

• Collaborating with front-end and back-end web developers.

TECHNORIO INC Kathmandu, Nepal Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

• Implemented the provided mockup using CSS and responsive CSS code.

- Collaborating with teams to implement the provided design, ensuring the feasibility of UI/UX designs.
- Enhancing the performance of the main front-end website.

EDUCATION

Internship

University Of Alabama In Huntsville

Huntsville, AL

Masters In Computer and Information Science

Graduation Date: Dec 2023